<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming Languages on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/categories/programming-languages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming Languages on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/categories/programming-languages/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Statically Typed Programming Language</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2017/08/05/typed-lambda-calculus-create-type-checker-transpiler-compiler-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2017/08/05/typed-lambda-calculus-create-type-checker-transpiler-compiler-javascript/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we&amp;rsquo;ll go through a sample implementation of a type checker, interpreter and a transpiler for a basic purely functional programming language, which is based on the lambda calculus. We will do a &amp;ldquo;full-stack&amp;rdquo; programming language development by going through formal definition of the language&amp;rsquo;s syntax, semantics and type system. After that we&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how we can &amp;ldquo;translate&amp;rdquo; these definitions to JavaScript.
Although the article doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any mathematical background, it&amp;rsquo;ll be useful to have high-level understanding of how compilers work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspect-Oriented Programming with AngularJS</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>In the following blog post I’ll write few words about what is Aspect-Oriented Programming, why I think it will be useful in AngularJS and I’m also going to give you a short tutorial for using a simple AOP framework I’ve developed.
First things first. What is AOP? As we all know OOP is awesome! It gives us many tools for making our development process simpler. Its core principles are Abstraction, Encapsulation, Inheritance and Polymorphism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical programming with JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2013/04/24/practical-programming-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2013/04/24/practical-programming-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Before few months I was invited by Telerik Academy to make a talk about JavaScript. Last Monday Marian Kostadinov, Radoslav Georgiev and me made a whole seminar about the topic. I’m addicted to the Object-Oriented programming so I choose to talk about that. You can find my slides at http://blog.mgechev.com/slides/javascript-patterns and a video (in Bulgarian) below in the post:
It was quite exciting for me to speak about this topic in front of about 200 people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript, the weird parts</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2013/02/22/javascript-the-weird-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2013/02/22/javascript-the-weird-parts/</guid>
      <description>To say that JavaScript is becoming more and more popular is such a typical and boring way to start such an awesome post&amp;hellip;Anyway, JavaScript is becoming more and more popular each day&amp;hellip;There’s client-side JavaScript with awesome API, you can do whatever you wish with it – write 3D games, stream video and audio, process files&amp;hellip;There’s also a server-side JavaScript which is also awesome (I guess awesome will be a common word for this post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional programming with JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2013/01/21/functional-programming-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2013/01/21/functional-programming-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>This article is about the functional concepts of JavaScript. Some of them are built-in the languages, others extra implemented but all of them are very common for purely functional languages like Haskell. First I want to tell what I mean with the term purely functional language. These languages are “safe”, they will not make side effect i.e. evaluating an expression won’t change something in the internal state and lead to different result of the same expression when called next time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELang</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2012/09/15/creating-your-own-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/amp/2012/09/15/creating-your-own-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>And one more blog post by me! It’s going to be in brand new topic than the others. For about an year and a half I’ve got an idea which I wanted to accomplish&amp;hellip;To create my own simple programming language. Actually it’s very useful task and quite interesting. Creating it you can get better understanding how the compilers and interpreters work and probably write better code. Unfortunately there were two problems&amp;hellip;I didn’t have enough time for such task and&amp;hellip;I’ve not studied formal grammars (and as I mentioned I don’t have enough time to study them&amp;hellip;there are just so much more interesting things to read about :-P ).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>