<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jquery on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/jquery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jquery on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/jquery/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional programming with JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/21/functional-programming-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/21/functional-programming-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>This article is about the functional concepts of JavaScript. Some of them are built-in the languages, others extra implemented but all of them are very common for purely functional languages like Haskell. First I want to tell what I mean with the term purely functional language. These languages are “safe”, they will not make side effect i.e. evaluating an expression won’t change something in the internal state and lead to different result of the same expression when called next time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carousel Gallery</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/carousel-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/carousel-gallery/</guid>
      <description>And one post in English&amp;hellip;For few days I’m developing one jQuery UI plugin. It’s picture gallery which I’ve seen in flash but not in JavaScript, that’s why I decided to fix this. The gallery is a set of rotating pictures and difference ways of handling the perspective. There’s nothing complicated in it just little analytic geometry. I haven’t used any canvases or SVG because I’ve wanted the biggest possible browser compatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color animation plugin for jQuery</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/01/16/color-animation-plugin-for-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/01/16/color-animation-plugin-for-jquery/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I haven’t wrote since a long time but there’s so much code and so little time&amp;hellip;It’s bad that the biggest part of the code is not open source but what can we do&amp;hellip;Last few hours I developed a JavaScript plugin for color animation. Of course for few hours I cant make something with great quality so it’s a little bit unstable (I think) but it works and it’s also valid for the JSLint standards.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>