<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mgechev.com/tags/development/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS in Patterns (Part 3)</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2014/07/05/angularjs-in-patterns-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2014/07/05/angularjs-in-patterns-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This publication aims to provide a more theoretical overview of some of the AngularJS components in order to show you how the things you are already familiar with (like different Object-Oriented Design Patterns) fit in the picture.  Link to the first part of the series. Link to the second part of the series.
This is the last blog post of the series &amp;ldquo;AngularJS in Patterns&amp;rdquo;. You can find the original GitHub repository, which contains all the information at github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS in Patterns (Part 2). Services.</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2014/06/08/angularjs-in-patterns-part-2-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2014/06/08/angularjs-in-patterns-part-2-services/</guid>
      <description>This publication aims to provide a more theoretical overview of some of the AngularJS components in order to show you how the things you are already familiar with (like different Object-Oriented Design Patterns) fit in the picture.  Link to the first part of the series.
This blog post continues the series &amp;ldquo;AngularJS in Patterns&amp;rdquo;. You can find the original GitHub repository, which contains all the information at github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS in Patterns (Part 1). Overview of AngularJS</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2014/05/08/angularjs-in-patterns-part-1-overview-of-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2014/05/08/angularjs-in-patterns-part-1-overview-of-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>In this series of blog posts I’m going to cover the paper I’m writing at GitHub.
It aims to provide a bit more theoretical overview of some of the AngularJS components in order to show you how the things you are already familiar with (like different Object-Oriented Design Patterns) fit in the picture.
Part one includes only a high level overview of AngularJS, enjoy it.
AngularJS overview AngularJS is JavaScript framework developed by Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The magic of $resource (or simply a client-side Active Record)</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2014/02/05/angularjs-resource-active-record-http/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2014/02/05/angularjs-resource-active-record-http/</guid>
      <description>At first sight AngularJS seems like a magical framework, which does some weird but awesome things like dependency injection, data binding only by setting a single property to the magical object named $scope and many other things.
If you look at the source code of Angular you’ll see a lot of smart and simple solutions for these magical problems. In this blog post I’ll describe the magic which stays behind $resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced JavaScript at Sofia University</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/24/advanced-javascript-in-sofia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/24/advanced-javascript-in-sofia-university/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I’ll tell few words about the course Advanced JavaScript which Georgi Penkov, Evgeni Kunev and me are leading this semester in Sofia University.
I was included as a lecturer in it after my project for Practical Programming with Perl (plainvm) which is created by Georgi Penkov. The idea behind the course is not to concentrate on the syntax of JavaScript but to introduce to the students different modern technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS style guide</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/06/angularjs-style-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/06/angularjs-style-guide/</guid>
      <description>Today I created a GitHub repository which contains a set of good practices and style guides for AngularJS application development.
Its main goal is to be community-driven and to concentrate all the best practices for AngularJS development in one place.
I’ve collected these guidelines mostly from my own experience and the source code of AngularJS. I guess there are missing things thats why I’ll try to fill the gaps in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC client on 200 lines of JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/30/vnc-javascript-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/30/vnc-javascript-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>In this quick blog post I’ll show you how to create a simple VNC client in about 200 lines of JavaScript. For our goal we’re going to use only HTML5 and JavaScript (client and server side). The end result will be something like this:

So, let’s begin!
Our application will have very simple architecture – a proxy server written in Node.js and a client in HTML5 and JavaScript. The Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspect-Oriented Programming with AngularJS</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>In the following blog post I’ll write few words about what is Aspect-Oriented Programming, why I think it will be useful in AngularJS and I’m also going to give you a short tutorial for using a simple AOP framework I’ve developed.
First things first. What is AOP? As we all know OOP is awesome! It gives us many tools for making our development process simpler. Its core principles are Abstraction, Encapsulation, Inheritance and Polymorphism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plainvm</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</guid>
      <description>plainvm can take the virtualization into different level of usage. To prove this I’ll first ask few rhetorical questions and put their answers&amp;hellip;Which is the programming language which everyone has interpreter for? Java? Actually no! Does iOS supports Java applets for example?! No! Everyone has a browser in his smartphone. Every browser (well may be I should exclude lynx, links&amp;hellip;) has JavaScript interpreter. And what is the common thing between all modern devices (and actually the devices most wide spread) – the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for performance? Probably you should NOT use [].sort (V8)</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/24/javascript-sorting-performance-quicksort-v8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/24/javascript-sorting-performance-quicksort-v8/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I’ve created a GitHub repository. It’s main goal was to collect different algorithms with implementations in JavaScript. I started with basic ones – sorting (insertion, selection, bubble sort..). After that I implemented few “more advance” like marge, quick and heap sort. It was interesting to me how much slower my implementation will be compared to the default sort. It was so interesting because of:
function sort() { [native code] }  That’s why I’ve wrote not optimized version of mergesort and I’ve run it with generated array with 500k elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript image scaling</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/02/javascript-html5-scale-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/02/javascript-html5-scale-image/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t wrote here for a while so I decided to write about something more practical. Actually the idea for the post come from one my response in stackoverflow. The post is connected with pure client side image scaling. While you’re reading the example I hope that you’ll see how powerful is the HTML5 API and how with few lines of code you can do something which in other technologies is much more complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 image editor</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/04/25/html5-image-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/04/25/html5-image-editor/</guid>
      <description>As you see HTML5 is everywhere (of course I exclude IE&amp;hellip;or just before version 10). Web site used for quick image composition or edition is something very useful for the “modern web person”. There are few such services. Most of them use Flash. Nothing against it but&amp;hellip;it’s too heavy for me&amp;hellip;unnecessarily heavy. For all that stuff you can use HTML5 canvas. I also found some HTML5 image editors but their functionality was very limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carousel Gallery</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/carousel-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/carousel-gallery/</guid>
      <description>And one post in English&amp;hellip;For few days I’m developing one jQuery UI plugin. It’s picture gallery which I’ve seen in flash but not in JavaScript, that’s why I decided to fix this. The gallery is a set of rotating pictures and difference ways of handling the perspective. There’s nothing complicated in it just little analytic geometry. I haven’t used any canvases or SVG because I’ve wanted the biggest possible browser compatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound notification in web page</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/01/cross-browser-sound-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/01/cross-browser-sound-notifications/</guid>
      <description>Few days ago I was creating a system in which it was necessary to implement a sound notification feature. Well it’s not very hard task but of course you have to be careful with the browser compatibility. At first my source was something like that:
playSound: function () { this.config.soundNotify.html(&amp;#39;&amp;lt;embed src=&amp;quot;&amp;#39; + this.config.soundFile + &amp;#39;.wav&amp;quot; hidden=true autostart=true loop=false&amp;gt;&amp;#39;); }  Actually in my Linux it was working pretty well (I tried it mainly in Chrome).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>f8</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2011/09/22/f8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2011/09/22/f8/</guid>
      <description>Ето нещо интересно, което ще можем да следим онлайн утре сутрин:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>