<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithms on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/Algorithms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithms on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/Algorithms/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lazy prefetching of AngularJS partials</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/01/angularjs-partials-lazy-prefetching-strategy-weighted-directed-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/01/angularjs-partials-lazy-prefetching-strategy-weighted-directed-graph/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is concentrated about web performance. I’ll skip the well known stuff about combining images into sprites, inlining images, DNS pre-fetching, combining and minifying script files, gzipping and so on. There are plenty of articles and tools which will help you about these things. There are also excellent researches on these topics, few of the best I’ve read are these by Mobify, Web Performance Daybook Volume, High Performance Web Sitesand Critical rendering path – Crash course on web performanceand many others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for performance? Probably you should NOT use [].sort (V8)</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/24/javascript-sorting-performance-quicksort-v8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/24/javascript-sorting-performance-quicksort-v8/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I’ve created a GitHub repository. It’s main goal was to collect different algorithms with implementations in JavaScript. I started with basic ones – sorting (insertion, selection, bubble sort..). After that I implemented few “more advance” like marge, quick and heap sort. It was interesting to me how much slower my implementation will be compared to the default sort. It was so interesting because of:
function sort() { [native code] } That’s why I’ve wrote not optimized version of mergesort and I’ve run it with generated array with 500k elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color animation plugin for jQuery</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/01/16/color-animation-plugin-for-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/01/16/color-animation-plugin-for-jquery/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I haven’t wrote since a long time but there’s so much code and so little time&amp;hellip;It’s bad that the biggest part of the code is not open source but what can we do&amp;hellip;Last few hours I developed a JavaScript plugin for color animation. Of course for few hours I cant make something with great quality so it’s a little bit unstable (I think) but it works and it’s also valid for the JSLint standards.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
