<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mvc on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/tags/mvc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mvc on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mgechev.com/tags/mvc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux in Depth. Store and Network Communication.</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2015/07/18/flux-in-depth-store-network-communication-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2015/07/18/flux-in-depth-store-network-communication-services/</guid>
      <description>This is the second, and probably be the last, blog post of the series &amp;ldquo;Flux in Depth&amp;rdquo;. In the first post we did a quick overview of flux, took a look at the stateless, pure components, immutable data structures and component communication. This time, we&amp;rsquo;re going to introduce the store and how we can communicate with services through the network via HTTP, WebSocket or WebRTC. Since the flux architecture doesn&amp;rsquo;t define a way of communication with external services, here you can find my way of dealing with network communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux in Depth. Overview and Components.</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2015/05/15/flux-in-depth-overview-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2015/05/15/flux-in-depth-overview-components/</guid>
      <description>This is the first blog post of the series &amp;ldquo;Flux in Depth&amp;rdquo;. Is this &amp;ldquo;yet the another flux tutorial&amp;rdquo;? What I have seen so far, while researching flux, were mostly &amp;ldquo;how-to&amp;rdquo; tutorials (usually with todo applications), which describe the main components of given flux application and the data flow between them. This is definitely useful for getting a high-level overview of how everything works but in reality there are plenty of other things, which should be taken under consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I should use publish/subscribe in JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/04/24/why-to-use-publishsubscribe-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/04/24/why-to-use-publishsubscribe-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>This post is inspired by my answer at StackOverflow.
So why we should use publish/subscribe? Why it is useful? Is it making our work harder or it makes our application better?
And the answer&amp;hellip;
It’s all about loose coupling and single responsibility, which goes hand to hand with MV* (MVC/MVP/MVVM) patterns in JavaScript which are very modern in the last few years.
Loose coupling is an Object-oriented principle in which each component of the system knows it’s responsibility and don’t care about the other components (or at least tries to not care about them as much as possible).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>