<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>React on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/react/</link>
    <description>Recent content in React on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/react/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Guess.js - a toolkit for enabling data-driven user-experiences on the Web</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/05/09/introducing-guess-js-data-driven-user-experiences-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/05/09/introducing-guess-js-data-driven-user-experiences-web/</guid>
      <description>About two months ago I published my initial research[1] on data-driven bundling. A few weeks after that, I had the opportunity to present my work on RenderConf in Oxford, UK in my talk &amp;ldquo;Teach Your Bundler Users&amp;rsquo; Habits&amp;rdquo;[2].
The original goal of the article was to show how data can help in improving the user-perceived page load performance by using predictive analytics[3]. The artifacts from the article were executable node modules which can be used for predictive pre-fetching &amp;amp; data-driven clustering of JavaScript chunks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Driven Bundling. The Future of JavaScript Tooling.</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/03/18/machine-learning-data-driven-bundling-webpack-javascript-markov-chain-angular-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/03/18/machine-learning-data-driven-bundling-webpack-javascript-markov-chain-angular-react/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce the early implementation of a few tools which based on techniques from the machine learning allow us to perform data-driven chunk clustering and pre-fetching for single-page applications. The purpose is to provide a zero-configuration mechanism which based on data from Google Analytics for the users&amp;rsquo; behavior performs the most optimal build. We&amp;rsquo;re also going to introduce a webpack plugin which works with Angular CLI and Create React App.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redux Anti-Patterns - Part 1. State Management.</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2017/12/07/redux-anti-patterns-race-conditions-state-management-duplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2017/12/07/redux-anti-patterns-race-conditions-state-management-duplication/</guid>
      <description>For the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project which uses React with TypeScript and Redux. In a few blog posts I&amp;rsquo;m planning to share lessons learned while combining these technologies. In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll share a few anti-patterns related to state management that I noticed in our development process. In the second article I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on testability.
All of the anti-patterns below have the following structure:
 Introduction Problem definition Sample solutions with discussion of their pros and cons  State Duplication Sometimes we have instances of the same business entity used in different contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Angular&#39;s Dependency Injection in React. Understanding Element Injectors.</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2017/01/30/implementing-dependency-injection-react-angular-element-injectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2017/01/30/implementing-dependency-injection-react-angular-element-injectors/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging mostly about Angular and it&amp;rsquo;s not by accident! Angular is an amazing framework, bringing a lot of innovation to the front-end technologies, with a great community behind it. In the same time, the projects that I&amp;rsquo;m working on have various of different requirements and sometimes I need to consider different options.
Another great technology that I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past is React. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to compare it with Angular; I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are variety of cases when one of them fits better compared to the other and visa versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux in Depth. Store and Network Communication.</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2015/07/18/flux-in-depth-store-network-communication-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2015/07/18/flux-in-depth-store-network-communication-services/</guid>
      <description>This is the second, and probably be the last, blog post of the series &amp;ldquo;Flux in Depth&amp;rdquo;. In the first post we did a quick overview of flux, took a look at the stateless, pure components, immutable data structures and component communication. This time, we&amp;rsquo;re going to introduce the store and how we can communicate with services through the network via HTTP, WebSocket or WebRTC. Since the flux architecture doesn&amp;rsquo;t define a way of communication with external services, here you can find my way of dealing with network communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using JSX with TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2015/07/05/using-jsx-react-with-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2015/07/05/using-jsx-react-with-typescript/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript is a weird language although, we love it the way it is. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve had quite a painful experience working on big JavaScript projects. It was painful in the same way it gets painful working on huge Ruby, Python, PHP projects.
Once you have code base above 10-15k lines of code and you decide to do some refactoring&amp;hellip;well it gets messy. Although grep and sed are powerful tools for text manipulation, when you start replacing code with them, you&amp;rsquo;re missing the semantics (or the context) of the snippets you substitute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux in Depth. Overview and Components.</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2015/05/15/flux-in-depth-overview-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2015/05/15/flux-in-depth-overview-components/</guid>
      <description>This is the first blog post of the series &amp;ldquo;Flux in Depth&amp;rdquo;. Is this &amp;ldquo;yet the another flux tutorial&amp;rdquo;? What I have seen so far, while researching flux, were mostly &amp;ldquo;how-to&amp;rdquo; tutorials (usually with todo applications), which describe the main components of given flux application and the data flow between them. This is definitely useful for getting a high-level overview of how everything works but in reality there are plenty of other things, which should be taken under consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebRTC chat with React.js</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2014/09/03/webrtc-peer-to-peer-chat-with-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2014/09/03/webrtc-peer-to-peer-chat-with-react/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;m going to share how could be build WebRTC chat with React.js. Before we continue lets describe briefly what React.js and WebRTC are.
The application from this tutorial is available at GitHub.
React.js React.js is reactive JavaScript framework, which helps you to build user interface. Facebook states that we can think of React as the &amp;ldquo;V&amp;rdquo; in MVC. React&amp;rsquo;s main aspect is the state. When the state of the application changes this automatically propagates through the application&amp;rsquo;s components.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>