<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/tags/internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mgechev.com/tags/internet/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced JavaScript at Sofia University</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/24/advanced-javascript-in-sofia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/24/advanced-javascript-in-sofia-university/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I’ll tell few words about the course Advanced JavaScript which Georgi Penkov, Evgeni Kunev and me are leading this semester in Sofia University.
I was included as a lecturer in it after my project for Practical Programming with Perl (plainvm) which is created by Georgi Penkov. The idea behind the course is not to concentrate on the syntax of JavaScript but to introduce to the students different modern technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspect-Oriented Programming with AngularJS</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>In the following blog post I’ll write few words about what is Aspect-Oriented Programming, why I think it will be useful in AngularJS and I’m also going to give you a short tutorial for using a simple AOP framework I’ve developed.
First things first. What is AOP? As we all know OOP is awesome! It gives us many tools for making our development process simpler. Its core principles are Abstraction, Encapsulation, Inheritance and Polymorphism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript, the weird parts</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/02/22/javascript-the-weird-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/02/22/javascript-the-weird-parts/</guid>
      <description>To say that JavaScript is becoming more and more popular is such a typical and boring way to start such an awesome post&amp;hellip;Anyway, JavaScript is becoming more and more popular each day&amp;hellip;There’s client-side JavaScript with awesome API, you can do whatever you wish with it – write 3D games, stream video and audio, process files&amp;hellip;There’s also a server-side JavaScript which is also awesome (I guess awesome will be a common word for this post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript image scaling</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/02/javascript-html5-scale-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/02/javascript-html5-scale-image/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t wrote here for a while so I decided to write about something more practical. Actually the idea for the post come from one my response in stackoverflow. The post is connected with pure client side image scaling. While you’re reading the example I hope that you’ll see how powerful is the HTML5 API and how with few lines of code you can do something which in other technologies is much more complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 image editor</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/04/25/html5-image-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/04/25/html5-image-editor/</guid>
      <description>As you see HTML5 is everywhere (of course I exclude IE&amp;hellip;or just before version 10). Web site used for quick image composition or edition is something very useful for the “modern web person”. There are few such services. Most of them use Flash. Nothing against it but&amp;hellip;it’s too heavy for me&amp;hellip;unnecessarily heavy. For all that stuff you can use HTML5 canvas. I also found some HTML5 image editors but their functionality was very limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carousel Gallery</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/carousel-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/carousel-gallery/</guid>
      <description>And one post in English&amp;hellip;For few days I’m developing one jQuery UI plugin. It’s picture gallery which I’ve seen in flash but not in JavaScript, that’s why I decided to fix this. The gallery is a set of rotating pictures and difference ways of handling the perspective. There’s nothing complicated in it just little analytic geometry. I haven’t used any canvases or SVG because I’ve wanted the biggest possible browser compatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound notification in web page</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/01/cross-browser-sound-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/01/cross-browser-sound-notifications/</guid>
      <description>Few days ago I was creating a system in which it was necessary to implement a sound notification feature. Well it’s not very hard task but of course you have to be careful with the browser compatibility. At first my source was something like that:
playSound: function () { this.config.soundNotify.html(&amp;#39;&amp;lt;embed src=&amp;#34;&amp;#39; + this.config.soundFile + &amp;#39;.wav&amp;#34; hidden=true autostart=true loop=false&amp;gt;&amp;#39;); }  Actually in my Linux it was working pretty well (I tried it mainly in Chrome).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>f8...</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/09/23/f8-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/09/23/f8-2/</guid>
      <description>Тази сутрин пуснах прословутата f8&amp;hellip;Бях с големи очаквания (дори поствах за нея), може би заради слабата ми информираност очаквах нещо като Google I/O (има си Google&amp;hellip;защо не потърсих предварително&amp;hellip;). Streaming-a тръгна и очаквано видях Марк Зукърбърг. Вместо той да говори за нови технологии и с какви средства е създал нещо ново, започна да прави реклама на новите feature-и на Facebook&amp;hellip;Дам трябваше да прочета повече преди да си настроя часовника да звъни толкова рано&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>f8</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/09/22/f8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/09/22/f8/</guid>
      <description>Ето нещо интересно, което ще можем да следим онлайн утре сутрин:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#43; API</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/09/16/google-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/09/16/google-api/</guid>
      <description>Като всеки любознателен developer и аз се включих към хората, които искат да получат mail от Google при пускането на API за Google+. Вчера (15-ти септември) около 1 часа получих следния mail:
 Getting Started on the Google+ API
Greetings developers,
Thank you for showing your interest in the Google+ platform on our developer interest form. We promised to let you know when we had more details to share. Well, that time has come&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>