<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Science on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/categories/computer-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Science on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mgechev.com/categories/computer-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing a Simple Compiler on 25 Lines of JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2017/09/16/developing-simple-interpreter-transpiler-compiler-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2017/09/16/developing-simple-interpreter-transpiler-compiler-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I already wrote a couple of essays related to the development of programming languages that I was extremely excited about! For instance, in &amp;ldquo;Static Code Analysis of Angular 2 and TypeScript Projects&amp;ldquo;[1] I explored the basics of the front end of the compilers, explaining the phases of lexical analysis, syntax analysis and abstract-syntax trees.
Recently I published &amp;ldquo;Developing Statically Typed Programming Language&amp;ldquo;[2]. This post shown a simple, statically typed, functional programming language inspired by lambda calculus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced JavaScript at Sofia University</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/24/advanced-javascript-in-sofia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/24/advanced-javascript-in-sofia-university/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I&amp;#8217;ll tell few words about the course Advanced JavaScript which Georgi Penkov, Evgeni Kunev and me are leading this semester in Sofia University.
I was included as a lecturer in it after my project for Practical Programming with Perl (plainvm) which is created by Georgi Penkov. The idea behind the course is not to concentrate on the syntax of JavaScript but to introduce to the students different modern technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy prefetching of AngularJS partials</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/01/angularjs-partials-lazy-prefetching-strategy-weighted-directed-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/01/angularjs-partials-lazy-prefetching-strategy-weighted-directed-graph/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is concentrated about web performance. I&amp;#8217;ll skip the well known stuff about combining images into sprites, inlining images, DNS pre-fetching, combining and minifying script files, gzipping and so on. There are plenty of articles and tools which will help you about these things. There are also excellent researches on these topics, few of the best I&amp;#8217;ve read are these by Mobify, Web Performance Daybook Volume, High Performance Web Sites and Critical rendering path &amp;#8211; Crash course on web performance and many others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC client on 200 lines of JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/30/vnc-javascript-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/30/vnc-javascript-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>In this quick blog post I&amp;#8217;ll show you how to create a simple VNC client in about 200 lines of JavaScript. For our goal we&amp;#8217;re going to use only HTML5 and JavaScript (client and server side). The end result will be something like this:

So, let&amp;#8217;s begin!
Our application will have very simple architecture &amp;#8211; a proxy server written in Node.js and a client in HTML5 and JavaScript. The Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspect-Oriented Programming with AngularJS</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>In the following blog post I&amp;#8217;ll write few words about what is Aspect-Oriented Programming, why I think it will be useful in AngularJS and I&amp;#8217;m also going to give you a short tutorial for using a simple AOP framework I&amp;#8217;ve developed.
First things first. What is AOP? As we all know OOP is awesome! It gives us many tools for making our development process simpler. Its core principles are Abstraction, Encapsulation, Inheritance and Polymorphism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional programming with JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/21/functional-programming-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/21/functional-programming-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>This article is about the functional concepts of JavaScript. Some of them are built-in the languages, others extra implemented but all of them are very common for purely functional languages like Haskell. First I want to tell what I mean with the term purely functional language. These languages are &amp;#8220;safe&amp;#8221;, they will not make side effect i.e. evaluating an expression won&amp;#8217;t change something in the internal state and lead to different result of the same expression when called next time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>