<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Browsers on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/Browsers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Browsers on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/Browsers/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VNC client on 200 lines of JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/30/vnc-javascript-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/30/vnc-javascript-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>In this quick blog post I’ll show you how to create a simple VNC client in about 200 lines of JavaScript. For our goal we’re going to use only HTML5 and JavaScript (client and server side). The end result will be something like this:

So, let’s begin!
Our application will have very simple architecture – a proxy server written in Node.js and a client in HTML5 and JavaScript. The Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS3 flipping effect</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/05/04/css3-flipping-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/05/04/css3-flipping-effect/</guid>
      <description>As you know because of the SIMD nature of the GPU it’s extremely good for graphical calculations. Since HTML5 and CSS3 are here we have a couple of ways for efficient and smooth animations one of them are the CSS3 transitions.
Before few days I needed a CSS3 flipping effect which should works at least in IE10, Chrome 25+ and Firefox. I tried different demos which I found in the web but there were couple of issues with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plainvm</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</guid>
      <description>plainvmcan take the virtualization into different level of usage. To prove this I’ll first ask few rhetorical questions and put their answers&amp;hellip;Which is the programming language which everyone has interpreter for? Java? Actually no! Does iOS supports Java applets for example?! No! Everyone has a browser in his smartphone. Every browser (well may be I should exclude lynx, links&amp;hellip;) has JavaScript interpreter. And what is the common thing between all modern devices (and actually the devices most wide spread) – the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for performance? Probably you should NOT use [].sort (V8)</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/24/javascript-sorting-performance-quicksort-v8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/24/javascript-sorting-performance-quicksort-v8/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I’ve created a GitHub repository. It’s main goal was to collect different algorithms with implementations in JavaScript. I started with basic ones – sorting (insertion, selection, bubble sort..). After that I implemented few “more advance” like marge, quick and heap sort. It was interesting to me how much slower my implementation will be compared to the default sort. It was so interesting because of:
function sort() { [native code] } That’s why I’ve wrote not optimized version of mergesort and I’ve run it with generated array with 500k elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript image scaling</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/02/javascript-html5-scale-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/02/javascript-html5-scale-image/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t wrote here for a while so I decided to write about something more practical. Actually the idea for the post come from one my response in stackoverflow. The post is connected with pure client side image scaling. While you’re reading the example I hope that you’ll see how powerful is the HTML5 API and how with few lines of code you can do something which in other technologies is much more complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound notification in web page</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/01/cross-browser-sound-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/01/cross-browser-sound-notifications/</guid>
      <description>Few days ago I was creating a system in which it was necessary to implement a sound notification feature. Well it’s not very hard task but of course you have to be careful with the browser compatibility. At first my source was something like that:
playSound: function () { this.config.soundNotify.html(&amp;#39;&amp;lt;embed src=&amp;#34;&amp;#39; + this.config.soundFile + &amp;#39;.wav&amp;#34; hidden=true autostart=true loop=false&amp;gt;&amp;#39;); } Actually in my Linux it was working pretty well (I tried it mainly in Chrome).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
