<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/machine-learning/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Mortal Kombat with TensorFlow.js. Transfer learning and data augmentation</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/10/20/transfer-learning-tensorflow-js-data-augmentation-mobile-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/10/20/transfer-learning-tensorflow-js-data-augmentation-mobile-net/</guid>
      <description>While experimenting with enhancements of the prediction model of Guess.js, I started looking at deep learning. I&amp;rsquo;ve focused mainly on recurrent neural networks (RNNs), specifically LSTM because of their &amp;ldquo;unreasonable effectiveness&amp;rdquo; in the domain of Guess.js. In the same time, I started playing with convolutional neural networks (CNNs), which although less traditionally, are also often used for time series. CNNs are usually used for image classification, recognition, and detection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Guess.js - a toolkit for enabling data-driven user-experiences on the Web</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/05/09/introducing-guess-js-data-driven-user-experiences-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/05/09/introducing-guess-js-data-driven-user-experiences-web/</guid>
      <description>About two months ago I published my initial research[1] on data-driven bundling. A few weeks after that, I had the opportunity to present my work on RenderConf in Oxford, UK in my talk &amp;ldquo;Teach Your Bundler Users&amp;rsquo; Habits&amp;rdquo;[2].
The original goal of the article was to show how data can help in improving the user-perceived page load performance by using predictive analytics[3]. The artifacts from the article were executable node modules which can be used for predictive pre-fetching &amp;amp; data-driven clustering of JavaScript chunks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Driven Bundling. The Future of JavaScript Tooling.</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/03/18/machine-learning-data-driven-bundling-webpack-javascript-markov-chain-angular-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/03/18/machine-learning-data-driven-bundling-webpack-javascript-markov-chain-angular-react/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce the early implementation of a few tools which based on techniques from the machine learning allow us to perform data-driven chunk clustering and pre-fetching for single-page applications. The purpose is to provide a zero-configuration mechanism which based on data from Google Analytics for the users&amp;rsquo; behavior performs the most optimal build. We&amp;rsquo;re also going to introduce a webpack plugin which works with Angular CLI and Create React App.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>