<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immediately Invoked Function Expression on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/categories/immediately-invoked-function-expression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Immediately Invoked Function Expression on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mgechev.com/categories/immediately-invoked-function-expression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC client on 200 lines of JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/30/vnc-javascript-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/30/vnc-javascript-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>In this quick blog post I’ll show you how to create a simple VNC client in about 200 lines of JavaScript. For our goal we’re going to use only HTML5 and JavaScript (client and server side). The end result will be something like this:

So, let’s begin!
Our application will have very simple architecture – a proxy server written in Node.js and a client in HTML5 and JavaScript. The Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-invoking functions in JavaScript (or Immediately Invoked Function Expressions)</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/08/29/self-invoking-functions-in-javascript-or-immediately-invoked-function-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/08/29/self-invoking-functions-in-javascript-or-immediately-invoked-function-expression/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of interesting things in the syntax of JavaScript, one of which is the definition of self-executing (self-invoking) functions. Here&amp;rsquo;s how we can defined such function:
(function () { //body of the function }());  The anonymous function above will be invoked right after it has been defined. The benefit of self-invoking functions is that they enable us to execute code once without cluttering the global namespace (without declaring any globals).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>