<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mgechev.com/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical programming with JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/04/24/practical-programming-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/04/24/practical-programming-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Before few months I was invited by Telerik Academy to make a talk about JavaScript. Last Monday Marian Kostadinov, Radoslav Georgiev and me made a whole seminar about the topic. I&amp;#8217;m addicted to the Object-Oriented programming so I choose to talk about that. You can find my slides at http://blog.mgechev.com/slides/javascript-patterns and a video (in Bulgarian) below in the post:
It was quite exciting for me to speak about this topic in front of about 200 people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plainvm</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</guid>
      <description>plainvm can take the virtualization into different level of usage. To prove this I&amp;#8217;ll first ask few rhetorical questions and put their answers&amp;#8230;Which is the programming language which everyone has interpreter for? Java? Actually no! Does iOS supports Java applets for example?! No! Everyone has a browser in his smartphone. Every browser (well may be I should exclude lynx, links&amp;#8230;) has JavaScript interpreter. And what is the common thing between all modern devices (and actually the devices most wide spread) &amp;#8211; the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for performance? Probably you should NOT use [].sort (V8)</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/24/javascript-sorting-performance-quicksort-v8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/11/24/javascript-sorting-performance-quicksort-v8/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I&amp;#8217;ve created a GitHub repository. It&amp;#8217;s main goal was to collect different algorithms with implementations in JavaScript. I started with basic ones &amp;#8211; sorting (insertion, selection, bubble sort..). After that I implemented few &amp;#8220;more advance&amp;#8221; like marge, quick and heap sort. It was interesting to me how much slower my implementation will be compared to the default sort. It was so interesting because of:
function sort() { [native code] }  That&amp;#8217;s why I&amp;#8217;ve wrote not optimized version of mergesort and I&amp;#8217;ve run it with generated array with 500k elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asus N56VZ &#43; Ubuntu 12.04 (en)</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/08/19/asus-n56vz-ubuntu-12-04-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/08/19/asus-n56vz-ubuntu-12-04-en/</guid>
      <description>It seems that it&amp;#8217;s common a problem to setup Ubuntu on the new Asus N56VZ so I decided to create an English version of my post.
I was struggling with three issues about two weeks. Here are they:
 Multimedia buttons (Fn+F*) Subwoofer Ethernet adapter  I&amp;#8217;ll start with the Subwoofer issue because it&amp;#8217;s with the easiest fix. Adding options snd-hda-intel model=asus-mode4 at the end of /etc/modprobe.d/alsa-base.conf  will solve the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asus N56VZ &#43; Ubuntu 12.04</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/07/22/asus-n56vz-ubuntu-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/07/22/asus-n56vz-ubuntu-12-04/</guid>
      <description>Един пост на български, защото мисля, че ще бъде по-полезен.
Доста време се тормозя с подкарването на разни feature-и на новия ми Asus N56 с Ubuntu 12.04 x86-64&amp;#8230;Мултимедия бутоните (комбинация между Fn+F*), съббуфера, като имах известни проблеми (не особени, но все пак трябва да се отбележат) и с ethernet.
И така, нека започна от съббуфера, защото решението е най-лесно. Добавянето на options snd-hda-intel model=asus-mode4 в края на /etc/modprobe.d/alsa-base.conf, решава проблема.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Squeeze &#43; LXDE on Google Nexus S (or having some fun while suffering)</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/07/08/debian-squeeze-lxde-on-google-nexus-s-or-having-some-fun-while-suffering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/07/08/debian-squeeze-lxde-on-google-nexus-s-or-having-some-fun-while-suffering/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m here again, after a long pause. For a while I&amp;#8217;ve got problems with my health and I&amp;#8217;m nailed at home&amp;#8230;so I&amp;#8217;ve go a lot of free time. Last night I&amp;#8217;ve decided to root my Google Nexus S.
I use Ubuntu

12.04 on my home machine so I put on it Oracle Java and Android SDK. I also installed few packages from the SDK (platform-tools). I created few udev rules, because my computer wasn&amp;#8217;t able to know what to do when I plug-in my Nexus with a fastboot mode.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>