<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>localStorage on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/tags/localStorage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in localStorage on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mgechev.com/tags/localStorage/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent State of ReactJS Component</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2015/03/05/persistent-state-reactjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2015/03/05/persistent-state-reactjs/</guid>
      <description>ReactJS is a framework, by facebook, which adds some well known concepts into the UI development. Each UI could be represented as a state machine but when the state of this state machine could be changed from a lot of places everything gets quite messy, complex and buggy. Given view may be rendered differently with the same model passed as parameter if it depends on some global data. A properly implemented ReactJS component, will be rendered the same way when the same &amp;ldquo;input parameters&amp;rdquo; are passed to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced JavaScript at Sofia University</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/24/advanced-javascript-in-sofia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/24/advanced-javascript-in-sofia-university/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I’ll tell few words about the course Advanced JavaScript which Georgi Penkov, Evgeni Kunev and me are leading this semester in Sofia University.
I was included as a lecturer in it after my project for Practical Programming with Perl (plainvm) which is created by Georgi Penkov. The idea behind the course is not to concentrate on the syntax of JavaScript but to introduce to the students different modern technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caching CSS with localStorage</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/09/04/caching-css-in-the-localstorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/09/04/caching-css-in-the-localstorage/</guid>
      <description>Since HTML5 became wide supported the most popular aspects I hear about were it’s canvas, WebSockets and localStorage. I’ve got very close experience with the first two of the mentioned but the localStorage was somehow unknown for me since a month. I’ve researched the topic. Actually it’s quite interesting and useful as you might guess. Using localStorage you can save different kinds of data locally into key-value pairs. The data lives on your local machine until it’s deleted (cleared).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>