<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mgechev.com/tags/projects/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS style guide</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/06/angularjs-style-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/06/angularjs-style-guide/</guid>
      <description>Today I created a GitHub repository which contains a set of good practices and style guides for AngularJS application development.
Its main goal is to be community-driven and to concentrate all the best practices for AngularJS development in one place.
I’ve collected these guidelines mostly from my own experience and the source code of AngularJS. I guess there are missing things thats why I’ll try to fill the gaps in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspect-Oriented Programming with AngularJS</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/08/07/aspect-oriented-programming-with-javascript-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>In the following blog post I’ll write few words about what is Aspect-Oriented Programming, why I think it will be useful in AngularJS and I’m also going to give you a short tutorial for using a simple AOP framework I’ve developed.
First things first. What is AOP? As we all know OOP is awesome! It gives us many tools for making our development process simpler. Its core principles are Abstraction, Encapsulation, Inheritance and Polymorphism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plainvm</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</guid>
      <description>plainvm can take the virtualization into different level of usage. To prove this I’ll first ask few rhetorical questions and put their answers&amp;hellip;Which is the programming language which everyone has interpreter for? Java? Actually no! Does iOS supports Java applets for example?! No! Everyone has a browser in his smartphone. Every browser (well may be I should exclude lynx, links&amp;hellip;) has JavaScript interpreter. And what is the common thing between all modern devices (and actually the devices most wide spread) – the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 image editor</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/04/25/html5-image-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/04/25/html5-image-editor/</guid>
      <description>As you see HTML5 is everywhere (of course I exclude IE&amp;hellip;or just before version 10). Web site used for quick image composition or edition is something very useful for the “modern web person”. There are few such services. Most of them use Flash. Nothing against it but&amp;hellip;it’s too heavy for me&amp;hellip;unnecessarily heavy. For all that stuff you can use HTML5 canvas. I also found some HTML5 image editors but their functionality was very limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Курсови проекти – ФМИ</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/03/31/%d0%ba%d1%83%d1%80%d1%81%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b5%d0%ba%d1%82%d0%b8-%d1%84%d0%bc%d0%b8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/03/31/%d0%ba%d1%83%d1%80%d1%81%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b5%d0%ba%d1%82%d0%b8-%d1%84%d0%bc%d0%b8/</guid>
      <description>Тъй като съм вече студент 3-ти курс във ФМИ и курсовите проекти се натрупаха, мисля че мога да бъда полезен на “младото поколение ФМИ-исти”, като предоставя една страница с връзки към кода, който съм разработил. Това ще можете да намерите в новата секция на блога ми “FMI Projects”.
Надявам се с това да помогна на студентите или да накарам преподавателите да проявят повече въображение в бъдещите задания към студентите :-).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>