<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/Build/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/Build/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Bazel Schematics for Angular CLI</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/12/17/introduction-bazel-schematics-angular-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/12/17/introduction-bazel-schematics-angular-cli/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we want to share our new schematics for Angular CLI which provide Bazel build support. You can find the implementation by Keen Liau on GitHub. With the @angular/bazel package, we want to let developers use Angular CLI with Bazel as a build tool.
What&amp;rsquo;s Bazel? Google open sourced the software responsible for building most of our projects under the name Bazel. Bazel is a powerful tool which can keep track of the dependencies between different packages and build targets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building TypeScript Projects with Bazel</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/11/19/introduction-bazel-typescript-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2018/11/19/introduction-bazel-typescript-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll make a brief introduction to what Bazel is and how we can build our TypeScript projects with it. If you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with the problems that Bazel solves, feel free to skip to the section &amp;ldquo;Building TypeScript with Bazel.&amp;rdquo; You can find the example from this blog post in my GitHub account.
Inside Google&amp;rsquo;s CI Google manages a massive amount of source code. There are dependencies between the individual projects, for example, the user interface of Google Cloud depends on Angular &amp;amp; Angular Material, Angular Material depends on Angular, which depends on TypeScript.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>