<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Any on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/Any/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Any on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mgechev.com/categories/Any/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AngularAOP v0.1.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/12/04/angularaop-v0-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/12/04/angularaop-v0-1-0/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I’ll introduce you the new way of annotating services included in AngularAOP v0.1.0.
First, why we need a new way for annotation? In v0.0.1 the annotations were made in services’ bodies. It was something like this:
myApp.factory(&amp;#39;AwesomeService&amp;#39;, function (execute, d1, d2,...,dn) { var api = /* definition of our service api */ return execute(Logger).onThrowOf(execute(Authorization).before(api, { methodPattern: /Special|getArticleById/, argsPatterns: [/^user$/, /^[Ii]d(_num)?$/] })); }); This way of annotating services led to coupling between the services and the API of the AngularAOP’s aspect factory service called execute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS style guide</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/06/angularjs-style-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2013/10/06/angularjs-style-guide/</guid>
      <description>Today I created a GitHub repository which contains a set of good practices and style guides for AngularJS application development.
Its main goal is to be community-driven and to concentrate all the best practices for AngularJS development in one place.
I’ve collected these guidelines mostly from my own experience and the source code of AngularJS. I guess there are missing things thats why I’ll try to fill the gaps in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Курсови проекти – ФМИ</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/03/31/%d0%ba%d1%83%d1%80%d1%81%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b5%d0%ba%d1%82%d0%b8-%d1%84%d0%bc%d0%b8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/03/31/%d0%ba%d1%83%d1%80%d1%81%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b5%d0%ba%d1%82%d0%b8-%d1%84%d0%bc%d0%b8/</guid>
      <description>Тъй като съм вече студент 3-ти курс във ФМИ и курсовите проекти се натрупаха, мисля че мога да бъда полезен на “младото поколение ФМИ-исти”, като предоставя една страница с връзки към кода, който съм разработил. Това ще можете да намерите в новата секция на блога ми “FMI Projects”.
Надявам се с това да помогна на студентите или да накарам преподавателите да проявят повече въображение в бъдещите задания към студентите :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carousel Gallery</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/carousel-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/carousel-gallery/</guid>
      <description>And one post in English&amp;hellip;For few days I’m developing one jQuery UI plugin. It’s picture gallery which I’ve seen in flash but not in JavaScript, that’s why I decided to fix this. The gallery is a set of rotating pictures and difference ways of handling the perspective. There’s nothing complicated in it just little analytic geometry. I haven’t used any canvases or SVG because I’ve wanted the biggest possible browser compatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SofiaJS...</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/sofiajs-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2012/02/16/sofiajs-2/</guid>
      <description>В потребителската група SofiaJS последните няколко месеца се случиха доста интересни неща, а на мен все не ми остава време, за да блогна за тях&amp;hellip; След хубавата лекция на Асен Божилов (за Google Chrome Extensions) и дискусията, която проведохме, Асен се включи активно в организацията и покани най-известния лектор, участвал в срещите – Стоян Стефанов. От своя страна Telerik указаха подкрепа, която оценявам, със своята покана лекцията да се проведе в тяхна зала.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SofiaJS</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/07/sofiajs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/07/sofiajs/</guid>
      <description>Преди няколко месеца внезапно (както май често става) започнах да мисля за програмиране (как ли така&amp;hellip;) и най-вече за JavaScript. Забелязах как все повече програмисти се насочват към този език, как все повече започва да се използва навсякъде (дори за server-side приложения) и все пак колко слабо е развито community-то в България. Бях взимал участие в .net потребителските групи и забелязах колко интересни дискусии се получават. Също така ми направи впечатление колко е приятно да се събират хора с еднакви интереси, на които работата им доставя истинско удоволствие (както е в моя случай).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound notification in web page</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/01/cross-browser-sound-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/11/01/cross-browser-sound-notifications/</guid>
      <description>Few days ago I was creating a system in which it was necessary to implement a sound notification feature. Well it’s not very hard task but of course you have to be careful with the browser compatibility. At first my source was something like that:
playSound: function () { this.config.soundNotify.html(&amp;#39;&amp;lt;embed src=&amp;#34;&amp;#39; + this.config.soundFile + &amp;#39;.wav&amp;#34; hidden=true autostart=true loop=false&amp;gt;&amp;#39;); } Actually in my Linux it was working pretty well (I tried it mainly in Chrome).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/07/14/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mgechev.com/2011/07/14/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hey,
That’s my first blog here. I’ll try to put some interesting stuff about the Life, Universe and Everything else but mostly I think&amp;hellip;about some technical topics.
I hope that you’re going to find interesting and useful information.
Have a nice read :).
See ya!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
