<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/categories/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu on Minko Gechev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mgechev.com/categories/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>plainvm</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2013/01/11/virtualization-into-the-browser/</guid>
      <description>plainvm can take the virtualization into different level of usage. To prove this I’ll first ask few rhetorical questions and put their answers&amp;hellip;Which is the programming language which everyone has interpreter for? Java? Actually no! Does iOS supports Java applets for example?! No! Everyone has a browser in his smartphone. Every browser (well may be I should exclude lynx, links&amp;hellip;) has JavaScript interpreter. And what is the common thing between all modern devices (and actually the devices most wide spread) – the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asus N56VZ &#43; Ubuntu 12.04 (en)</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/08/19/asus-n56vz-ubuntu-12-04-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/08/19/asus-n56vz-ubuntu-12-04-en/</guid>
      <description>It seems that it’s common a problem to setup Ubuntu on the new Asus N56VZ so I decided to create an English version of my post.
I was struggling with three issues about two weeks. Here are they:
 Multimedia buttons (Fn+F*) Subwoofer Ethernet adapter  I’ll start with the Subwoofer issue because it’s with the easiest fix. Adding options snd-hda-intel model=asus-mode4 at the end of /etc/modprobe.d/alsa-base.conf  will solve the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asus N56VZ &#43; Ubuntu 12.04</title>
      <link>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/07/22/asus-n56vz-ubuntu-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mgechev.com/2012/07/22/asus-n56vz-ubuntu-12-04/</guid>
      <description>Един пост на български, защото мисля, че ще бъде по-полезен.
Доста време се тормозя с подкарването на разни feature-и на новия ми Asus N56 с Ubuntu 12.04 x86-64&amp;hellip;Мултимедия бутоните (комбинация между Fn+F*), съббуфера, като имах известни проблеми (не особени, но все пак трябва да се отбележат) и с ethernet.
И така, нека започна от съббуфера, защото решението е най-лесно. Добавянето на options snd-hda-intel model=asus-mode4 в края на /etc/modprobe.d/alsa-base.conf, решава проблема.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>